<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Blog &#8211; Indonesia Yanwoo</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/blog/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 03:10:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-FAVICON-SARANGWALET-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Blog &#8211; Indonesia Yanwoo</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Employee Salary and Business Profit Potential of Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest in Indonesia</title>
		<link>/employee-salary-and-business-profit-potential-of-edible-birds-nest-in-indonesia</link>
					<comments>/employee-salary-and-business-profit-potential-of-edible-birds-nest-in-indonesia#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[akdeaso]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 06:12:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sarangwalet.test/?p=1696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Getting to know the salary at Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest Factory Edible bird&#8217;s nest has become an increasingly popular product in Indonesia, especially in the culinary industry. However, before reaching consumers, edible bird&#8217;s nest goes through a series of production processes in edible bird&#8217;s nest factories. Behind the success of this product, there are hardworking and &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/employee-salary-and-business-profit-potential-of-edible-birds-nest-in-indonesia"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Employee Salary and Business Profit Potential of Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest in Indonesia</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="1696" class="elementor elementor-1696">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-5e2037f3 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="5e2037f3" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-6b8f21f6" data-id="6b8f21f6" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-50bf2f8f elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="50bf2f8f" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
			<style>/*! elementor - v3.11.2 - 22-02-2023 */
.elementor-widget-text-editor.elementor-drop-cap-view-stacked .elementor-drop-cap{background-color:#818a91;color:#fff}.elementor-widget-text-editor.elementor-drop-cap-view-framed .elementor-drop-cap{color:#818a91;border:3px solid;background-color:transparent}.elementor-widget-text-editor:not(.elementor-drop-cap-view-default) .elementor-drop-cap{margin-top:8px}.elementor-widget-text-editor:not(.elementor-drop-cap-view-default) .elementor-drop-cap-letter{width:1em;height:1em}.elementor-widget-text-editor .elementor-drop-cap{float:left;text-align:center;line-height:1;font-size:50px}.elementor-widget-text-editor .elementor-drop-cap-letter{display:inline-block}</style>				<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Getting to know the salary at Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest Factory</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Edible bird&#8217;s nest has become an increasingly popular product in Indonesia, especially in the culinary industry. However, before reaching consumers, edible bird&#8217;s nest goes through a series of production processes in edible bird&#8217;s nest factories. Behind the success of this product, there are hardworking and dedicated employees in the edible bird&#8217;s nest factories.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Of course, as employees, they are entitled to receive a decent salary. How much do edible bird&#8217;s nest factory workers actually earn? According to information obtained, the salary of edible bird&#8217;s nest factory workers ranges from Rp 1,400,000 to Rp 2,600,000. However, the amount of salary also depends on many factors, such as work experience, position, and work location. Some companies also provide additional allowances such as health and attendance allowances.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In addition to salary, edible bird&#8217;s nest factory workers also receive other facilities such as health and accident insurance, meal allowances, and annual leave. Because edible bird&#8217;s nest production is usually done seasonally, some companies also provide bonuses during harvest time. Therefore, even though the salary of edible bird&#8217;s nest factory workers is not as high as other industries, with the facilities and other allowances provided, it can help improve the welfare of employees.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Profiting from the Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest Business</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Aside from being an employee, some people choose to open an edible bird&#8217;s nest business. This business can provide substantial profits but also requires a significant initial investment. However, if successful, the edible bird&#8217;s nest business can provide very promising profits.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>For your information, one gram of edible bird&#8217;s nest is valued at around 20,000 Indonesian Rupiah, which means you can earn 20 million Rupiah if you successfully sell 1 kilogram alone. However, the price can also vary depending on the quality and location of the sale. In addition to selling raw edible bird&#8217;s nest, you can also obtain even greater profits by producing food or beverages made from the edible bird&#8217;s nest.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>However, to succeed in the edible bird&#8217;s nest business, you must pay attention to several factors, such as the quality of the edible bird&#8217;s nest produced, the breeding techniques used, and proper marketing. Moreover, the edible bird&#8217;s nest business also requires patience and perseverance, as the production of edible bird&#8217;s nest is considered seasonal and requires a significant amount of time and care. However, if done seriously and consistently, the edible bird&#8217;s nest business can provide substantial and sustainable profits.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>From the above discussion, it can be concluded that the salary of a swallow nest factory worker is not very high, but still within the range of regional minimum wage. However, despite the modest salary, the swallow nest business itself has the potential for significant profits. With the high selling price of one gram of swallow bird&#8217;s nest, this business can generate significant profits. However, starting this business requires a large investment and a considerable amount of time to achieve the desired results.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Therefore, if you are interested in starting a swallow nest business, make sure to prepare yourself well and conduct research beforehand. Find information on how to obtain high-quality swallow bird&#8217;s nest seedlings, how to care for the birds, and how to obtain high-quality swallow nests. Additionally, make sure to factor in the necessary costs, such as investment, operational, and marketing costs.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In starting a swallow nest business, you may also consider collaborating with a swallow nest factory. This can help you obtain a wider market, reduce marketing costs, and receive technical assistance from the factory in caring for the birds and obtaining high-quality swallow nests. However, make sure to choose a reliable and reputable factory in the swallow nest industry.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Finally, the swallow nest business is not easy, but if managed well, it can become a promising source of income. It requires determination, hard work, and perseverance to succeed in this business. Don&#8217;t forget to continuously develop your knowledge and skills in the swallow nest industry so that you can adapt to market changes and maximize profits.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/employee-salary-and-business-profit-potential-of-edible-birds-nest-in-indonesia/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Harvesting Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest: How Often and How Many Times a Year?</title>
		<link>/harvesting-edible-birds-nest-how-often-and-how-many-times-a-year</link>
					<comments>/harvesting-edible-birds-nest-how-often-and-how-many-times-a-year#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[akdeaso]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 04:42:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sarangwalet.test/?p=1690</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Edible bird&#8217;s nest has become increasingly popular as a food ingredient lately, especially due to its claimed benefits for boosting the immune system and enhancing skin beauty. Edible bird&#8217;s nest is made from the hardened and sticky saliva of swiftlet birds that is shaped into a nest. However, due to the difficulty of finding edible &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/harvesting-edible-birds-nest-how-often-and-how-many-times-a-year"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Harvesting Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest: How Often and How Many Times a Year?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="1690" class="elementor elementor-1690">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-3c3567da elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="3c3567da" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-524a89f6" data-id="524a89f6" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-632fd0dd elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="632fd0dd" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Edible bird&#8217;s nest has become increasingly popular as a food ingredient lately, especially due to its claimed benefits for boosting the immune system and enhancing skin beauty. Edible bird&#8217;s nest is made from the hardened and sticky saliva of swiftlet birds that is shaped into a nest. However, due to the difficulty of finding edible bird&#8217;s nests in the wild, many farmers now develop edible bird&#8217;s nest breeding businesses. For those who want to start an edible bird&#8217;s nest breeding business, the common question is how often is the harvest of edible bird&#8217;s nests and how many times a year can the harvest be done?</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Before discussing the harvest schedule for edible bird&#8217;s nests, it is important to know how to cultivate edible bird&#8217;s nests properly. Firstly, it is necessary to ensure the availability of a suitable and optimal environment for the swiftlet birds to reproduce and create nests. This can be done by creating a special room with suitable temperature and humidity conditions for swiftlet birds. Secondly, choosing the right type of feed and giving it regularly to keep the swiftlet birds healthy and productive in creating nests. Thirdly, maintaining environmental cleanliness and providing adequate ventilation to keep the swiftlet birds comfortable and free from disease.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>After understanding how to cultivate edible bird&#8217;s nests properly, it is time to discuss the harvest schedule for them. Generally, the harvest of edible bird&#8217;s nests can be done 2-3 times a year. However, the harvest schedule may vary depending on the type of swiftlet birds being raised and environmental factors in the breeding location. For example, for swiftlet birds of the swiftlet species, the harvest schedule can be done every 2 months. This is because swiftlet birds of the swiftlet species have a high reproduction rate and require a relatively short time to create nests. However, for white-nest swiftlet birds, the harvest schedule for edible bird&#8217;s nests can be done every 3 months.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>To ensure the proper schedule for edible bird&#8217;s nest harvest, it is recommended to regularly observe and monitor the birds. This is aimed at ensuring the quality and quantity of edible bird&#8217;s nests produced by the birds and minimizing the risk of losses due to inedible nests. Additionally, monitoring of the breeding environment is crucial to maintain the health and comfort of the birds and prevent the spread of diseases.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In conclusion, the harvest schedule for edible bird&#8217;s nests can be carried out 2-3 times a year depending on the type of bird and the breeding environment. Regular observation and monitoring of the birds and the breeding environment can help ensure the right harvest schedule and minimize risks. Proper and good breeding practices are also essential in maintaining the health of the birds and the quality of the edible bird&#8217;s nests produced. By considering these factors, it is hoped that the business of breeding edible bird&#8217;s nests can run successfully and produce high-quality nests.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/harvesting-edible-birds-nest-how-often-and-how-many-times-a-year/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest and Bird Droppings Have High Economic Value, but Are They Dangerous to Health?</title>
		<link>/edible-birds-nest-and-bird-droppings-have-high-economic-value-but-are-they-dangerous-to-health</link>
					<comments>/edible-birds-nest-and-bird-droppings-have-high-economic-value-but-are-they-dangerous-to-health#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[akdeaso]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 03:46:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sarangwalet.test/?p=1649</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What are edible bird&#8217;s nests made of? Edible bird&#8217;s nest is considered a luxury product and has a quite high price. Edible bird&#8217;s nest is made from the basic material of bird saliva that contains a special substance that can harden when exposed to air. In addition to saliva, edible bird&#8217;s nest can also be &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/edible-birds-nest-and-bird-droppings-have-high-economic-value-but-are-they-dangerous-to-health"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest and Bird Droppings Have High Economic Value, but Are They Dangerous to Health?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="1649" class="elementor elementor-1649">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-23bc4f00 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="23bc4f00" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-299d483f" data-id="299d483f" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-738995eb elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="738995eb" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>What are edible bird&#8217;s nests made of?</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Edible bird&#8217;s nest is considered a luxury product and has a quite high price. Edible bird&#8217;s nest is made from the basic material of bird saliva that contains a special substance that can harden when exposed to air. In addition to saliva, edible bird&#8217;s nest can also be mixed with other materials such as plant fibers and bird feathers.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The process of forming edible bird&#8217;s nest takes a quite long time and goes through several stages. The initial stage starts with birds searching for a suitable place to build their nest. Birds usually look for places with high humidity, such as caves or under bridges.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>After finding a suitable place, the bird will start producing saliva that will be used to form the nest. The saliva produced contains high levels of sugar and protein, which will then oxidize with air to harden into a nest-shaped structure.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Is edible bird&#8217;s nest harmful?</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Bird&#8217;s nest guano, also known as bird droppings, has been widely used in various applications, including as a natural fertilizer and raw material for chemical production. However, despite its significant benefits, bird&#8217;s nest guano also has some potential dangers to human health.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>One potential danger of bird&#8217;s nest guano is the presence of harmful microorganisms such as bacteria, fungi, and viruses. Some of these microorganisms can cause respiratory infections, such as pneumonia, when inhaled in large quantities. Therefore, it is important to avoid direct exposure to bird droppings dust and wear a mask when cleaning or processing it.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In addition, bird&#8217;s nest guano can also contain heavy metals such as lead and mercury, especially if the birds that produce the droppings consume contaminated food. Long-term exposure to heavy metals can cause damage to internal organs such as the kidneys and liver. Therefore, it is important to ensure that the source of bird&#8217;s nest guano used is free from heavy metals or has been processed and tested before use.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>However, despite its potential hazards to human health, bird&#8217;s nest guano is still widely used in various applications, especially in the agricultural industry as a natural fertilizer. As an alternative, bird&#8217;s nest guano can be processed into organic fertilizer that is safer and free from harmful microorganisms and heavy metals. In addition, wearing a mask when processing bird droppings can also help reduce the risk of exposure to harmful dust and microorganisms.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In the cosmetics industry, bird&#8217;s nest guano has also been used in some products such as face creams and masks. However, consumers need to be careful when using cosmetic products containing bird&#8217;s nest guano and choose products that have undergone adequate sterilization and testing to ensure product safety.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Edible bird&#8217;s nest is made from the saliva of swiftlets. It has a high economic value as a luxury food item and is used in some cosmetic products. However, the bird&#8217;s nest&#8217;s excrement also has the potential to be harmful to human health due to the presence of dangerous microbes and heavy metals. Therefore, it is necessary to carry out adequate sterilization and testing processes before using edible bird&#8217;s nest, and it is essential to wear a mask when processing or cleaning it. As an alternative, edible bird&#8217;s nest can also be processed into organic fertilizers that are safer and free from the dangers of microbes and heavy metals.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/edible-birds-nest-and-bird-droppings-have-high-economic-value-but-are-they-dangerous-to-health/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What is the lifespan of Swiftlets?</title>
		<link>/what-is-the-lifespan-of-swiftlets</link>
					<comments>/what-is-the-lifespan-of-swiftlets#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[akdeaso]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 03:33:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sarangwalet.test/?p=1644</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The swiftlet, also known as the edible-nest swiftlet, is a type of bird that has high economic value due to its ability to make expensive edible bird&#8217;s nest. However, not many people know how long swiftlets live and what factors influence their lifespan.   Age of Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest How long can swiftlets survive? The &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/what-is-the-lifespan-of-swiftlets"> <span class="screen-reader-text">What is the lifespan of Swiftlets?</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="1644" class="elementor elementor-1644">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-49240c61 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="49240c61" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-4a8a1e10" data-id="4a8a1e10" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-4a94450b elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="4a94450b" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The swiftlet, also known as the edible-nest swiftlet, is a type of bird that has high economic value due to its ability to make expensive edible bird&#8217;s nest. However, not many people know how long swiftlets live and what factors influence their lifespan.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Age of Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>How long can swiftlets survive? The lifespan of swiftlets can vary depending on several factors. Some factors that can affect the lifespan of swiftlets are their living environment, gender, health condition, and the care given to them.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Typically, swiftlets can survive up to the age of around 15 to 18 years. However, some swiftlets are known to live longer than that. Nonetheless, the long lifespan of swiftlets cannot be determined for certain, as like any other bird, their lifespan is also influenced by many factors such as their living conditions and their own health.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Factors that Affect the Age of Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>There are several factors that can affect the age of a swiftlet. Firstly, the environmental factor of their habitat. Swiftlets usually live in hard-to-reach areas, such as caves, tall trees, and high-rise buildings. If the environment where the swiftlets live is well-preserved, they can live longer and healthier.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Secondly, gender can also affect the age of swiftlets. Female swiftlets usually have a longer lifespan compared to male swiftlets. This is because female swiftlets are more active in finding food and collecting materials to make nests.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Thirdly, the health condition of the swiftlets also affects their lifespan. Swiftlets that are healthy and well-cared for tend to live longer. Therefore, special care is needed to maintain the health of swiftlets, such as providing healthy food, keeping the environment clean, and giving vaccinations if needed.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In conclusion, the age of a swiftlet can vary depending on several factors such as the environmental condition of their habitat, gender, health condition, and care provided. Swiftlets that live in a good environment and receive special care tend to live longer. As swiftlet owners, it is important to give proper attention and care to ensure that they can live longer and healthier.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/what-is-the-lifespan-of-swiftlets/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest: High Nutritional Value, but Halal Status Needs to Be Considered</title>
		<link>/edible-birds-nest-high-nutritional-value-but-halal-status-needs-to-be-considered</link>
					<comments>/edible-birds-nest-high-nutritional-value-but-halal-status-needs-to-be-considered#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[akdeaso]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 03:25:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sarangwalet.test/?p=1636</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest: Source of Amino Acids and Heart Health Edible bird&#8217;s nest, which is produced from the saliva of swiftlets, is one of the most expensive food ingredients in the world. Many people consume it because it is believed to have high health benefits. Edible bird&#8217;s nest contains essential amino acids required by the &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/edible-birds-nest-high-nutritional-value-but-halal-status-needs-to-be-considered"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest: High Nutritional Value, but Halal Status Needs to Be Considered</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="1636" class="elementor elementor-1636">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-2814e3df elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="2814e3df" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-4a707f05" data-id="4a707f05" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-39b32ac3 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="39b32ac3" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest: Source of Amino Acids and Heart Health</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Edible bird&#8217;s nest, which is produced from the saliva of swiftlets, is one of the most expensive food ingredients in the world. Many people consume it because it is believed to have high health benefits. Edible bird&#8217;s nest contains essential amino acids required by the body, including lysine and arginine which help to increase muscle mass and strengthen the immune system. Additionally, the collagen content in edible bird&#8217;s nest also helps to improve skin and hair structure.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Not only that, but several studies also indicate that edible bird&#8217;s nest can help maintain heart health. Edible bird&#8217;s nest contains bioactive compounds that help reduce the risk of cardiovascular disease and stabilize blood pressure. Furthermore, edible bird&#8217;s nest also helps to increase good cholesterol (HDL) in the body which can help maintain heart health.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>However, it is advisable to consult a doctor or nutritionist before consuming edible bird&#8217;s nest, especially for people with certain medical conditions such as allergies or specific health problems.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Swiftlet: Prohibited for Consumption According to Shafi&#8217;i and Hanbali Scholars</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Swiftlets, which produce edible bird&#8217;s nest, have become controversial when it comes to discussing whether they can be consumed or not. According to Shafi&#8217;i and Hanbali scholars, swiftlets are considered haram or prohibited for consumption. The reason being that swiftlets do not have clear indications as to whether they are halal or haram. Additionally, swiftlets also have physical characteristics that resemble scavenger birds, such as their small heads and long beaks.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>However, in some countries such as China and Vietnam, swiftlets are still considered a delicious and nutritious food. Nevertheless, in Indonesia, swiftlets are more well-known as producers of edible bird&#8217;s nest rather than as a food ingredient.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest: Halal and Needs to be Purified</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>According to the fatwa of the Majelis Ulama Indoensia (MUI), bird&#8217;s nest is considered halal for consumption. However, if the bird&#8217;s nest is mixed with or contaminated by impurities such as excrement, then it must be purified according to shariah (tathhir syari&#8217;i) before consumption. The procedure for tathhir syari&#8217;i for bird&#8217;s nest can refer to MUI&#8217;s fatwa No. 2 of 2010.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>It is important to note that although bird&#8217;s nest is considered halal, if it is obtained by damaging the habitat of swiftlets, then such a method is clearly unethical and environmentally harmful. Therefore, as consumers, we also need to choose bird&#8217;s nest products from trusted and environmentally friendly sources, and pay attention to the halal label on the products.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Overall, bird&#8217;s nest can be consumed and has benefits for the body&#8217;s health, but it must be obtained in an environmentally friendly and halal manner. Meanwhile, swiftlets as livestock are prohibited in Islam and the sustainability of swiftlets&#8217; population in the wild must be preserved. Therefore, as consumers, we also need to choose bird&#8217;s nest products from trusted and environmentally friendly sources, and pay attention to the halal label on the products.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/edible-birds-nest-high-nutritional-value-but-halal-status-needs-to-be-considered/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Making Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest in Your Own Swiftlet House: Procedures and Maintenance</title>
		<link>/making-edible-birds-nest-in-your-own-swiftlet-house-procedures-and-maintenance</link>
					<comments>/making-edible-birds-nest-in-your-own-swiftlet-house-procedures-and-maintenance#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[akdeaso]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 03:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sarangwalet.test/?p=1626</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Getting to Know Swiftlets and Their Farming Techniques Swiftlet is a bird known for its unique ability to create its nest. The edible bird&#8217;s nest is the most expensive food in the world and is commonly used in traditional Chinese cuisine. When it comes to the cultivation of edible bird&#8217;s nest, there are several things &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/making-edible-birds-nest-in-your-own-swiftlet-house-procedures-and-maintenance"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Making Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest in Your Own Swiftlet House: Procedures and Maintenance</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="1626" class="elementor elementor-1626">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-284acd40 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="284acd40" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-747c0816" data-id="747c0816" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-5e504f1c elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="5e504f1c" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Getting to Know Swiftlets and Their Farming Techniques</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Swiftlet is a bird known for its unique ability to create its nest. The edible bird&#8217;s nest is the most expensive food in the world and is commonly used in traditional Chinese cuisine. When it comes to the cultivation of edible bird&#8217;s nest, there are several things that need to be known, one of which is how the nest is formed.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The edible bird&#8217;s nest is formed from the saliva that is excreted by the swiftlet when it creates its nest in hard-to-reach caves. The swiftlet will fly around the cave and excrete saliva that will form the nest when the saliva comes into contact with the air and dries up. The process of nest formation takes a considerable amount of time and can last for weeks to months.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Why is the Swiftlet Chosen for Cultivation?</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The swiftlet bird is the most widely cultivated bird by farmers worldwide. There are several reasons why swiftlets are chosen for cultivation, one of which is the potential for high profits. Edible bird&#8217;s nest is a very expensive food ingredient and can reach millions of rupiahs per kilogram.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In addition, swiftlet farming is also considered an environmentally friendly business. In the process of cultivating swiftlets, no chemicals or fertilizers are required, so it does not have a negative impact on the surrounding environment. Furthermore, swiftlets can also help reduce the population of insects and pests around the breeding area, making the surrounding environment healthier.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>How to Breed Swiftlets in a Swiftlet House</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>One way to cultivate swiftlets is by building a swiftlet house. A swiftlet house is a specialized building designed for breeding swiftlets and producing edible bird&#8217;s nests. The swiftlet house is usually built in a remote location away from crowds because swiftlets can be easily disturbed by too much activity around them.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Typically, a swiftlet house is built with a special design that resembles natural caves. The swiftlet house must have the right temperature and humidity to make the swiftlets comfortable and productive in making their nests. In addition, the swiftlet house must be equipped with special equipment such as sound systems and adjustable lighting that can be customized to the conditions of the swiftlets.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In cultivating swiftlets, farmers must pay attention to several things, such as the health of the swiftlets, the cleanliness of the swiftlet house, as well as good nutrition and care for the swiftlets.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/making-edible-birds-nest-in-your-own-swiftlet-house-procedures-and-maintenance/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest: Revealing Capital, Price, and Export Potential of the World&#8217;s Most Expensive Food</title>
		<link>/edible-birds-nest-revealing-capital-price-and-export-potential-of-the-worlds-most-expensive-food</link>
					<comments>/edible-birds-nest-revealing-capital-price-and-export-potential-of-the-worlds-most-expensive-food#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[akdeaso]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 02:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sarangwalet.test/?p=1621</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Capital Investment for Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest: Expensive but Profitable Edible bird&#8217;s nest or also known as bird&#8217;s nest is one of the most expensive food ingredients in the world. It is produced by swiftlets from their saliva that they use to make their nests in hard-to-reach caves. Therefore, it is difficult to gather edible bird&#8217;s &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/edible-birds-nest-revealing-capital-price-and-export-potential-of-the-worlds-most-expensive-food"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest: Revealing Capital, Price, and Export Potential of the World&#8217;s Most Expensive Food</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="1621" class="elementor elementor-1621">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-4a0d2e15 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="4a0d2e15" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-9c17f79" data-id="9c17f79" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-376b8953 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="376b8953" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Capital Investment for Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest: Expensive but Profitable</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Edible bird&#8217;s nest or also known as bird&#8217;s nest is one of the most expensive food ingredients in the world. It is produced by swiftlets from their saliva that they use to make their nests in hard-to-reach caves. Therefore, it is difficult to gather edible bird&#8217;s nests in large quantities, making them very expensive.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The capital required to start an edible bird&#8217;s nest business is not small, it can even reach up to Rp500 million. This is because the production process requires special equipment and technology, and must be done carefully and meticulously to avoid damaging the edible bird&#8217;s nests that already exist in the caves.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>The High Nutritional Content Makes Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest an Expensive Product</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>One of the reasons for the high price of edible bird&#8217;s nest is its high nutritional content that is believed to maintain good health. Edible bird&#8217;s nest contains many nutrients such as protein, amino acids, carbohydrates, calcium, phosphorus, iron, and collagen. These nutrients are believed to improve skin, hair, and nail conditions, as well as boost the immune system. In addition, it is still difficult to cultivate edible bird&#8217;s nest because the production process requires a specific environmental condition and the birds themselves only produce nests in limited amounts.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>Price of Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest Per Ounce: How Expensive is it?</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>The price of edible bird&#8217;s nest per ounce can vary greatly depending on its quality and place of purchase. However, the average price for high-quality edible bird&#8217;s nest in the market can reach around IDR 1.8 million to IDR 2 million per ounce. This high price makes edible bird&#8217;s nest a highly exclusive product that can only be afforded by a small percentage of people.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>
<p><!-- wp:heading {"level":3} --></p>
<h3>The Potential for Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest Export: Regulations and Requirements to Consider</h3>
<p><!-- /wp:heading --></p>
<p><!-- wp:paragraph --></p>
<p>Although expensive, edible bird&#8217;s nest remains a sought-after and in-demand product in the international market. Edible bird&#8217;s nest can be exported from its country of origin with proper permits and requirements. However, each country has different regulations and requirements regarding the export of edible bird&#8217;s nest.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Some countries require permits and certifications from health regulatory bodies or the government before edible bird&#8217;s nest can be exported, while others have limitations or prohibitions on the export of edible bird&#8217;s nest. Therefore, entrepreneurs who want to start an edible bird&#8217;s nest business need to pay attention to the regulations and requirements in their country before exporting.</p>
<p><!-- /wp:paragraph --></p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/edible-birds-nest-revealing-capital-price-and-export-potential-of-the-worlds-most-expensive-food/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Benefits of Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest for Human Health</title>
		<link>/benefits-of-edible-birds-nest-for-human-health</link>
					<comments>/benefits-of-edible-birds-nest-for-human-health#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[akdeaso]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 07:48:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sarangwalet.test/?p=1582</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Some people may doubt the safety of edible bird&#8217;s nests as a food. However, the consumed edible bird&#8217;s nests are processed and taken from the nests of the swiftlets that live in certain caves. Edible bird&#8217;s nests that are consumed are usually called Edibles Bird Nest. One of the benefits of edible bird&#8217;s nests is &#8230;<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/benefits-of-edible-birds-nest-for-human-health"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Benefits of Edible Bird&#8217;s Nest for Human Health</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="1582" class="elementor elementor-1582">
									<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-c90f5c7 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default" data-id="c90f5c7" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-e10c09b" data-id="e10c09b" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
								<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-23e27ba elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="23e27ba" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
							<p>Some people may doubt the safety of edible bird&#8217;s nests as a food. However, the consumed edible bird&#8217;s nests are processed and taken from the nests of the swiftlets that live in certain caves. Edible bird&#8217;s nests that are consumed are usually called Edibles Bird Nest.</p><p> </p><p>One of the benefits of edible bird&#8217;s nests is its ability to help maintain skin beauty. Edible bird&#8217;s nests contain Epidermal Growth Factor (EGF) which can enhance the body&#8217;s ability to produce natural collagen. This natural collagen helps maintain skin elasticity and softness, making the skin look more youthful, bright, and even whitening the skin.</p><p> </p><p>In addition to beauty benefits, edible bird&#8217;s nests also have incredible health benefits. Some of the health benefits of edible bird&#8217;s nests include:</p><p> </p><h5>1. Reducing the risk of heart disease</h5><p>Edible bird&#8217;s nest can help control blood thickness and maintain stable cholesterol levels, minimizing the risk of heart attacks.</p><p> </p><h5>2. Source of minerals and antioxidants</h5><p>Edible bird&#8217;s nest is rich in antioxidants and active compounds that can counteract the effects of free radicals. These antioxidants help prevent various chronic diseases that can harm the body, such as cancer. In addition, the mineral content such as calcium, manganese, and copper in edible bird&#8217;s nest can help with bone growth, carbohydrate metabolism, enzyme activation, collagen production, and many other benefits.</p><p> </p><h5>3. Source of protein or amino acids</h5><p>Edible bird&#8217;s nest is a food with the most complete protein content, containing all types of amino acids needed by the body.</p><p> </p><h5>4. Preventing insulin resistance</h5><p>Edible bird&#8217;s nest can reduce excessive insulin production and also break down fat to be more effective.</p><p> </p><h5>5. Reducing the impact of nicotine</h5><p>The substances contained in edible bird&#8217;s nest can function as a controller of harmful addictive substances in the body, as edible bird&#8217;s nest has a high antioxidant content.</p><p> </p><h5>6. Enhancing brain development in fetuses and toddlers</h5><p>The highly complete amino acid content in edible bird&#8217;s nest can meet the needs of nerve cell intake in the brains of fetuses and toddlers. This is very important to support growth and development. EGF in edible bird&#8217;s nest also helps stimulate brain cell growth more effectively.</p><p> </p><h5>7. Strengthening bone cells in the elderly</h5><p>Amino acids and protein have been proven to be beneficial in renewing cells in the human body and improving the metabolic system. We know that human metabolism tends to slow down as we age, so consuming edible bird&#8217;s nest can help improve it.</p>						</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
							</div>
		</section>
							</div>
		]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/benefits-of-edible-birds-nest-for-human-health/feed</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
